Juan Pablo Bravo Celi, MBA, CCMP

Duesseldorf, 40225, Germany | +49 178 1123-416 | juanpablo.bravoc@gmail.com | LinkedIn: juanpablobravoceli

SUMMARY

Digital Transformation & IT Strategy Executive with over 13 years of experience driving large-scale digital and operational implementations (\$5M+) for leading multilateral organizations (IDB, UNDP, OAS) and Fortune Global 500 corporations (75K+ employees, 130+ countries) in the finance and insurance sector across Washington D.C., Latin America, and Europe. Proven record in designing and executing organization-wide strategies, delivering IT solutions, and leading strategic change programs impacting 5K+ stakeholders across 40+ markets. Expert in leading cross-functional, multicultural teams to deliver high-impact digital transformation, operational excellence initiatives, and advanced technology adoption. Certified in Change Management, Agile Methodologies, and Innovation & Change Leadership.

EDUCATION

Frankfurt School of Finance & Management (FS) – Frankfurt am Main, Germany

Sep. 2019 – Dec. 2020

• Master of Business Administration (MBA) with specializations in Finance & Technology

Amazon – Amazon Web Services – Internship and Consultancy Thesis Project

Apr. 2020 - Oct. 2020

"Go-to-Market Strategy for the 'AWS re/Start' Program, DACH Region"

SDA Bocconi – Milan, Italy

Sep. 2020 – Sep. 2020

• MBA Exchange Program: earned a certificate in Leadership of Innovation & Change

Florida State University (FSU) – Tallahassee, FL, USA

Aug. 2007 - Dec. 2011

• Bachelor of Science, Double Major in International Affairs and Political Science

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Marsh (Marsh) (Marsh McLennan)

Duesseldorf, Germany

Digital Transformation Leader, Client-Facing Solutions – Continental Europe

Apr. 2022 - Jul. 2024

- Designed the regional strategy and roadmap for client-facing solutions across 35+ countries, leading the launch and rollout of the company's first digital client portal. Achieved a 250% AAGR in client onboarding within the first 2 years.
- Led and mentored a cross-functional, regional team of 20+ PMs to rollout a client portal across Europe's largest markets.
- Advised CCOs and CEOs across multiple countries on tailored digital value propositions, securing over 65% of new businesses where digital services were a crucial factor, including a client with 250+ accounts across 25 countries.
- Established a client-centric *Continuous Improvement* operational framework to product development, boosting adoption rates to 60% in key markets, reducing change requests by 50%, and improving usability and satisfaction KPIs.
- Optimized regional data management processes by collaborating with the Europe COO to streamline local operations, standardize data entry, and automate 40% of the data validation process. This reduced client onboarding time by over 60% and enhanced the digital customer experience.
- Managed the digitally enabled portfolio for Risk Management & Corporate clients, generating over USD 19M in revenue and USD 200M in insurance premiums while maintaining operational excellence and delivering top-tier service quality.

Digital Client Experience Manager, Client Platform Lead – Continental Europe

Mar. 2021 – Apr. 2022

- Developed and executed the Go-To-Market strategy for Marsh's first global client digital solution across the top four European markets, securing Steering Committee and stakeholder endorsement of the roadmap and value proposition.
- Led a regional team of 10+ specialists (DA, PO, BA, CMP) to launch the digital portal pilot program, driving IT awareness initiatives across Europe while ensuring operational readiness, resource allocation, and reliable KPIs.
- Assessed key industry trends in IT solutions and advised CCOs & CEOs on local investment objectives.

Inter-American Development Bank (<u>IDB</u>)

Washington D.C., USA

IT Adoption Project Manager Consultant (Innovation & IT Unit)

Jul. 2016 – May 2019

- Led the digitalization process and optimization of 20+ core business operations, partnering with key stakeholders and Business Owners (BOs) to ensure a functional alignment with Business Units' strategic and operational goals.
- Developed IT Transformation roadmaps and Change Management strategies for 15+ new technologies and digitized services—components of the new Enterprise System—ensuring seamless integration and adoption in 26 country offices.

- Implemented a new agile product-design strategy integrating feedback from key stakeholders and Unit Chiefs, ensuring the highest business value, operational efficiency, and boosting digital platform adoption by 2.5K users in 18 months.
- Established agile management practices by including BOs in Vendor's sprint reviews and early user testing, resulting in a 70% reduction in change requests and achieving a 90% UAT sign-off rate (30% increase).
- Deployed 20+ IT products and services through phased rollouts, ensuring adoption by implementing tailored training programs with reliable feedback systems, and advising Directors on suitable tech to support operational goals.
- Led a team of 6 developers based in Argentina through the design, development, and implementation of a <u>Stata</u>-embedded web portal, mitigating IT security challenges to ensure safe external access to the bank's education datasets.

Digital Transformation & Change Management Consultant (Technology Department) May 2015 – Jul. 2016

- Designed and implemented a pilot program to evaluate and drive the early adoption of the new O365 collaboration tools, collecting metrics on usability, UX, and training needs, ensuring an efficient deployment across the organization.
- Assessed pilot program data insights with Microsoft specialists to address usability and performance issues and informed the decision-making process while solving operational challenges and adoption risks.
- Designed and executed the Change Management strategy for the O365 tools including marketing & communication plans, an Early Adopters Program, and IT training programs—virtual and on-site workshops—impacting 2K+ users.
- Established operational metrics—adoption rate, usage, Jira support tickets, and satisfaction surveys—to monitor the progress of technology implementation and track the successful adoption by 4.5K+ users across 26 countries.

Communications Management Consultant (Office of External Relations)

Jan. 2015 – May 2015

• Developed and executed a 3-month awareness campaign, in a TED Talk-style, promoting 16 innovative startups and their value propositions, providing international visibility towards angel investors & venture capitalists in 35 countries.

Organization of American States (OAS) Rusiness Anglest (Young American Rusiness Trust -

Washington D.C., USA

Sep. 2013 - Jul. 2014

- Business Analyst (Young Americas Business Trust YABT)
- Co-led the operational planning and execution of the 2014 Talent & Innovation Competition of the Americas.
- Developed partnerships and gained investors across academia, government agencies, and private-sector agents in LAC.
 Led a team of 5 professionals to mentor 100+ entrepreneurs in building business models and creating effective pitch decks to showcase to the Paraguay's PM and OAS Secretary General during the Venture Night event in Asuncion, PR.

Plan International (Regional Office of the Americas – ROA)

Panama City, Panama

Public-Private Partnerships & Fundraising Intern (Strategic Alliances, Private Sector Unit)

Jul. 2013 - Sep. 2013

- Developed market research on corporate social responsibility programs in Latin America's private sector and delivered a structured report to inform the decision-making process for building new partnerships and gaining donors.
- Evaluated Salesforce and Blackbaud CRMs software as potential tools for managing Plan's regional client portfolio.

DHL EXPRESS (Americas)

Panama City, Panama

Asia-Pacific Business Accounts Officer (Commercial Unit)

Mar. 2012 - May 2013

• Built and managed an Asia-Pacific clients' portfolio by identifying core business needs and mitigating performance risks.

United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) – Regional Office for LAC

Panama City, Panama

Research Assistant Intern for the Economic & Political Section (Human Development Unit) May 2011 – Aug. 2011

• Supported the market strategy and development of the UNDP's National Human Development Report (NHDR).

LANGUAGES • English: Fluent • French: Professional Level • Spanish: Native • German: Basic (B.1)

CERTIFICATES & AWARDS

- Certified Professional Change Management (CPCM) The Knowledge Academy Washington, D.C., USA (2019)
- Received Outstanding Performance Staff Awards IDB Washington, D.C., USA (2016 & 2018)
- Certificate in Business Florida State University (FSU) Tallahassee, FL, USA (2010)

SKILLS • Agile Transformation • IT Strategy • Change Management • Digitalization • PO • GenAl • Team Leadership

Negotiation • People Manager • Stakeholder Management • Strategic Thinking • IT Marketing • IT Comms